Baikie West Coast of Scotland.
Is this for the carrier?
No, I am expecting a car.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I don't seem to be.
What's it now?
What are you crying for?
Get up, please!
What do you mean? Who are you?
Get up! Turn around a minute.
You don't want this. Do you?
Anyway, it isn't yours.
Disgusting!
There you are, Mary darling!
The lady is quite finished with it.
Would you like some spit?
No thank you.
Nothing I can do?
Well, you can take this
to the end of the pier.
What, all of them?
Oh, never mind, don't trouble.
Paris-London.
You've been to Paris.
Yes.
- Doing what?
- Finishing school.
Ha, ha...
Finished being finished?
- Yes!
- Good!
Your penny, please!
- My what?
- Your penny landing fee!
- But I've landed!
- Your penny, please!
The... Gentleman
there has my luggage.
Very good, Miss.
Come on, move!
Will you please observe... I have no hand
to pick up my pouch?
What are you doing with this?
Why, I'm Miss Victoria's driver.
Oh, I see! No, that's is mine!
Here you are!
- Miss Victoria?
- Ay.
Victoria?
That's a grand name!
- Oh, come on, please!
- We want to pass!
Hey!
Honoria Hegarty...
Open in the name of law!
And no nonsenses here!
Looks like we've to effect an entry.
Ay, looks like one of us has
to effect an entry.
Look what you're doing, man!
Will you confine your
operations to the door?
Stop it now!
Would you have me house in ruins
and me and Patsy in the midst of them?
Ay, it's Patsy we are after.
Bring him up, and let him come quite.
He's nothing of the sort
"come quiet".
Then I'll break the door down.
Now, just you try it.
One!
Two!
Three!
You're obstructing the law?
It's the law's obstructing me!
The law wants to get him!
And what's he done?
And him as innocent as a newborn angel!
You should have paid the license!
License is it?
If a grand big country like this...
Is needing 7 shillings and 6 p.
From the likes of me...
It's time it gets on the dole
the same as the rest of us.
Oh man, dear!
It's not the license money!
It's the fine!
Five pounds!
Ay, for persistent infringement.
Where would the like of me
get five pounds?
Standing next to naked
in the dead of summer...
With the wind whistling down
from the North Pole, and me...
Trying to sell ice cream
for a bunch of frozen customers.
Patsy!
Get him down!
Come on, Patsy.
Well, well!
Give me back me dog! Patsy!
- Let me take it!
- You should have paid the fee!
You've had enough, riff-raff?
Will you disperse and go
to your business!
You've great want of shame, Sergeant!
The girl is for sanatorium!
Why aren't you using your guns?
Evil, that's what it is!
It's massacre.
I'll have the law deal with you!
Patsy, me lovely Patsy!
- Well, who are you?
- I am Maggie.
- Where's Jessie?
- She left!
- You'll be Miss Victoria?
- Yes.
I'm sorry, I can't help it.
Oh, it's OK by me!
That's a relief.
- Where is the Provost?
- He's dead busy.
And what's all this?
A football match?
Politics, he's in there with
Baillie Callender.
I see.
Go and unpack my things, will you?
OK.
And don't say OK.
Right-o.
Oh, and tell me!
Why did Jessie leave?
Oh, she didn't approve!
Citizens of Baikie, in full confidence
of your loyalty...
I, your Provost, invite your presence
at my inaugural meeting...
At the Town Hall, Baikie,
on Friday next.
Signed, William Gow.
Good edit, Callender?
Ay... A bit personal.
That's it, don't you see?
Psychology.
Oh, psychology.
Loyalty! That's a fine word,
they can't resist it.
Hello, Vickie!
- My dear!
- Father!
Oh it's good to see you again!
How are you Baillie?
Man, but you've turned
into a great madam!
Changed a lot since
you fell in my pig sty.
Yes, yes, don't bother
about pigsties now...
We got to get to that council meeting.
Talking of meetings,
you might have met me at the pier.
I'm sorry about that, Vickie, but it was
absolutely impossible.
Your father's a busy man,
there's great things forthcoming.
I'm... I'm standing for Parliament, Vickie.
I know that.
I have seen a few posters.
But you don't know why I'm standing.
You see, Vickie.
These are exceptional times.
And such times require
exceptional measures.
And exceptional men.
Hear, hear.
Being Provost of Baikie
is all very well in it's way, but...
Could you do that, Callender?
Yes.
I've done my best for the place,
tried to keep it up to date.
I've built them a new Town Hall,
a new swimming pool...
The most elaborate
public conveniences...
A curbside for the tourists.
I hope you haven't spoiled Baikie, father.
They said in the Advertiser, that I'm
the best administrator in the country.
I'm sure you're a great success.
I should be. I work hard enough.
Tomorrow I'm opening the
Croy Cattle Show...
And I've my big election
meeting at night...
And the day after... Now this is strictly
confidential, Vickie...
Lord Skerryvore is coming.
Who is Lord Skerryvore?
Why, the leader of the
Party, of course.
You look that he comes
to see the Provost...
The Provost doesn't go to see him!
Well...
He knows I have the
Caledonia League behind me.
And it's not Baikie: All of Scotland.
But Scotsmen all over the Empire.
Ay, it's a big thing, a grand big thing.
There's no saying how big it may be.
If I pull this off,
the time may come...
when I shall be listened to by whole world!
The profession of journalism
is an honourable one.
What?
The profession of journalism
is honourable!
Oh! Oh yes, yes.
I have nothing to be ashamed of
in the conduct of my paper.
What?
I have nothing to be ashamed of...
Oh, good.
Nothing sensational ever
enters my columns.
Why not?
I said...
- Sit down!
- Yes.
- Oh no, not there. Over there.
- Sorry.
Mr. Burdon...
You've joined the most wide read paper
on the West Coast.
So it was bound to be.
Will you have a cigarette?
No smoking in hours!
Mr. Burdon...
A reporter of the Advertiser has a
position of very great trust.
Now, I'm on to Manchester tonight
but unfortunately my sub-editor is in bed.
I'm sorry, what's the trouble?
- He's got lumbago.
- Ah.
But the point is, I promised our Provost
a page in tomorrow's issue.
And you'll have to take the interview
and see it to the press.
Now, can you do that Burdon?
No smoking!
Yes, of course.
Yes, what's the...
what's the article about?
Well, Provost Gaw is
standing for the new Party.
What's new about it?
For one thing, Scotland for the Scottish.
Oh, does somebody else want it?
That'll do, Burdon.
Mrs. Skirving.
Horace, we'll miss that train!
Well, I'm waiting for you.
Oh, Mr Burdon, my wife.
- How do you do?
Well, you can't expect the Colonel's lady
to extend her manners to me.
I beg your pardon?
Well, away over to Town Hall
to get the interview with the Provost.
Yes!
The Town Hall is that
ghastly building, isn't it?
I'll have you know the Provost built it!
Oh...
Then I'll take
another look at it.
What a little brat!
He is English... I think.
Well, it's away, or we'll miss the train.
- I'll look on Willie and say goodbye.
- What for?
Willie's lovely Town Hall!
Is that all?
- Yes, Provost.
- Then you can go.
You'll be coming in to the meeting soon?
Baillie Callender is having
a sour time in the chair.
I'll be around in a minute, now clear out.
Victoria, you better go up into the gallery
to see the front.
Father, can I ask you something?
Well, I'm rather busy.
Why did you sack Jessie?
Jessie, what?
Oh, the parlour maid!
She got a bit above herself, Vickie...
and Lisbeth very kindly
disposed of her for me.
Lisbeth?
Now, who's mentioning my name?
Why Victoria, I wouldn't
have recognized you.
How nice of you to look in
and welcome me back!
Yes...
You've quite grown up, dear.
Willie, I just look in to say goodbye.
That was good of you, Lisbeth.
- Be back in time for the meeting.
- Oh, don't you worry!
I couldn't do without you on the platform.
No, I don't think you could.
Well, I'm to the station now, or Horace
will have the jitters.
How is Horace?
Just his old self.
Gentlemen please, you're wasting time.
The Provost has decided.
Next business!
Item no. 7: The bathing drawers for the
instructors of the new swimming pool.
As chairman of the Cleansing
and Parks committee...
I've looked in these
drawers very carefully.
And they certainly present some problems.
This is the sort of garment
that I would suggest...
But Mr. Deputy Chairman, the instructors
complained that are not practical.
They can not swim in them.
So there we're back to
the old problem...
Whether we should choose
the trunks of the knee long kind...
Or the trunks of the short kind...
In other words...
Either we decide upon an adequately
discreet trunk with limited mobility...
Or desire a good mobility
without adequate discretion.
Neither, in my opinion,
are really satisfactory.
We have to satisfy...
I move that the bathing drawers
are on the table. Sit down!
Next business!
Item no. 8:
Supply a new hose for the fire brigade.
- Hello!
- Hello.
- What are you doing here?
- Just getting up to date.
You won't get that one here!
This is a very serious matter.
Mr. Syme, that's got nothing
to do with the question.
I move that the whole matter be postponed
for further investigation.
But Mr. Provost...
Will you kindly resume your seat?
Next business!
Overbearing kind of bloke, isn't he?
- Who?
- The headmaster.
Mr. Provost...
With regard to my
objection to that...
Don't bring that up again please!
You made a mistake!
I don't think so!
The trouble is, you don't think at all!
Next business.
If she is not very careful, she'll be put
in the corner for getting out of line.
I've an application from Ross,
the stoker of the municipal laundry...
Asking for a raise of a half pound a week.
- On what grounds?
- The same old grounds!
His good lady presented him with twins.
In my view, if we grant
this application we're
only asking for a
fourth pair of twins.
Suppose he had four pairs of twins.
On second thought, thanks
to the Lord he hasn't.
Gentlemen...
We've something more important to discuss
than Mr. Ross' weekly milk bill.
We'll hand the merit to the
Ways and Means committee.
We will now discuss my
scheme for publicizing
Baikie throughout the Country
as a tourist resort.
You had copies of the detailed memorandum
I've drawn up.
And...
I'll assume that you all have taken
the trouble to read it.
That fellow give me a pain in the neck.
Oh dear...
Honoria!
McKellen, where in heavens
may have you been?
- You can't come here.
- No, nor can I do anything else!
I can't sit here with my two hands folded
in front of me like a mummy.
But they're about to adjourn,
the Provost will be coming.
It's himself I'm after!
Oh, he won't see you, Honoria.
He won't avoid it!
There was one important item
that was not on the agenda.
We're wanting your
authorization for the purchase
of new nutrition plants
for the orphanage.
What happened to the old ones?
Why, the orphans ate the seeds.
- They did, did they?
- Ay.
- I'll look into that Mr Thompson.
- Thank you, Mr. Provost.
One moment Mr. Provost, Your Honour...
You know all about me
since I know all about you...
It's meself, Honoria Hegarty.
Not a word now!
I know what you want to say.
Don't say it!
It's all very fine and large as the law,
don't I know!
And I know you can't make exceptions!
They tell me all that at the office.
I know it's all on your good word!
But it's why I'm telling you
it's all nonsense!
Will you kindly stop talking and
get out of my way!
Listen, Honoria...
- Excuse me, sir.
- Yes, what do you want?
Nothing. I was told
I had to interview you.
Oh, you are from the Advertiser!
Do you mind coming home with me?
Not at all. I'll...
Wait till you attend to this lady.
Your Honour, it's not meself
I'm thinking on, it's Patsy.
My little Patsy, he's the heart and soul
of me body, I'm telling you no lie.
If he goes, I go too.
Up to heaven among the blessed saints.
And it'll be all your fault!
If you annoy me any further
I'll have you locked up!
- Come along, Mr...
- Burdon, but...
Are you coming?
Get in!
Go on then!
Move up!
Oh, this is my
daughter, Victoria.
Move up!
- How do you do?
If you knew my Patsy, you wouldn't have a
grin the like that all over your face.
Oh, but I know him all right!
What's that? You know him?
Well, in a manner of speaking,
he's lodging here with me!
You con me!
Look in the chest, Honoria.
Patsy, me son!
Why, the light of this woman's life!
Oh me beautiful Patsy,
me lovely Patsy!
And what in the name of the holy
apostolates, is he doing here...
In your own apartment,
in a wooden box?
They couldn't have him
at the police station.
You see, it's this way...
The police Sgt. Bull... Terrier
bitch, she...
Well, what is it man, speak out.
Oh, for heaven's sake...
And so the borough chief
has given me the custody.
- He is a fine little fellow!
- He is that, Honoria.
He eats like a wee wolf.
He loves his bread
with milk for breakfast.
- I made him a nice ball of rice.
- He's eating all right, darling.
Well, hmm...
I feel kind of funny with him around.
He makes a sort of condemned cell
atmosphere of this my lodgings.
What's that?
What'd you say...
You don't mean...
Ay...
They can't! They can't!
- Come on, Come on!
- Yes.
- Sit down!
- Oh, thanks.
- No, not there, not there, there.
- Sorry.
I hear you're turning politician, Mr. Gow.
Politician? Ah! Statesman!
Father wants to be Prime Minister
of the first Scotch Parliament.
Scottish, Vickie, Scottish!
Help yourself to a Scottish and soda!
I'll leave you to it.
Hey, what's your name, you there...
Just a second, Mr. Gow.
You've no cause to be jumping about
like a poodle in this house. Sit down!
Stagnation of public life.
What, sir?
- I'm dictating.
- Oh, so sorry!
Don't I take notes and then
write it up for you?
Write it up?
Yes, er... put it into English.
You'll kindly put down exactly what I say.
I'm away to the cattle
show early in the morning
and I want a proof of
the interview tonight.
Yes, very good.
Stagnation of public life.
Wanted, new men.
Provost Gow's plain words to the electors.
During my term of office...
as Provost of Baikie...
I have been instrumental...
In bringing about great
changes in the borough.
But...
There's one change I that shall never make.
A change in the principles that guide me.
No, no, of course not.
You can't come in here, the boss is busy!
Look, I know that, he's busy righting
wrong. Well, here's another for him.
I advise you to scram!
- All right, Maggie.
- God bless you, ma'am.
May the Good Lord
look after you...
And look slash into your eyes!
Ma'am dear, it's your
father I'm seeking for.
I'm afraid he is giving an interview.
Oh, the poor soul.
And I'm deeply concerned
with the well being
of every individual
in the community.
But ma'am it can't wait.
It's a matter of life and death,
it's about my little Patsy.
Why, what's the little boy done?
Your Honour, is about my Patsy.
- How dare you burst in here?
- Father!
Burst or not, I got to do
what I got to do.
Well, do it somewhere else!
I think some of her boys
has gotten into a strait.
- I warned you at the Town Hall.
- But she said it's very urgent!
And now you have the insolence
to come cantering into my private house.
I think if we got the little chappy
here and talk to him.
If you talk to him,
he'll bark at you.
Bark at you?
Victoria, are you mad?
Show her out of here at once!
And understand, Mrs. Hegarty...
The case of your dog is
finished once and for all!
Dog?
But you told me this
was about your little son!
No, I asked you to be kind
but you mistook me.
Not that he's not like a son to me!
And now...
Now they're going to kill him.
What rubbish!
Who's going to kill a little dog?
The corporation, and the police
and the Provost.
Father!
Is this true about Mrs.
Hegarty's little dog?
She's persistently defied the law
in the matter of the dog tax.
- But father...
- She's been warned time and time again.
- But it's only 7 shillings and 6 pence.
- She's been fined and she won't pay that!
But it's only 7 shillings
and 6 pence, surely...
The court passed judgement
and quite rightly.
The town is full of little mongrel dogs!
- The state of the pavement!
- How much does she owe?
Five pounds and the tax!
- But surely they can make an exception.
- No, no, no.
On peut payer pour Elle.
- Mais non! Mais non!
- Pourquoi pas?
Il s'agit de... principles.
Jamais d'un Principe, toujours d'un homme.
Hear, hear!
If you are so keen on dogs,
save up and get a new one!
- A new dog? A new dog?
- And next time, pay the tax.
Vickie, put her out.
Now, what was I saying before that
unconscionable interlude?
You were concerned of the well being
of every individual in the community.
I'm asking my friends
in Baikie to give me
an opportunity of applying
these principles.
I'll subscribe!
What?
Unless you want to settle
on the quite, of course.
You mean for that woman?
I wouldn't pay a penny, on principle!
Wouldn't it be advisable?
Especially if you are asking people
to vote for you.
Thank you very much!
Will you kindly mind your own business!
I am asking my friends in Baikie...
To give me an opportunity
of applying these principles.
Get yourself out!
Get out I said!
Blooming Irish...
Get inside!
Now...
Where was I?
"Applying these principles."
Ah, yes... In a wider field.
It is for realization...
That each unit in the State...
Is a living, breathing soul...
Will you get on?
Living, breathing soul...
Each with its own intense perception
of his own rights and his own wrongs.
A leader must have that
strange sixth sense...
Which enables him to see
into the hearths of his people!
The Provost wishes to make
the corrections, Burdon.
"Mr." Burdon.
- Hack away!
- Hack away yourself! To bed!
Go on!
Are you gonna keep the machines
waiting all night?
Probably.
Here, no smoking within hours!
Here, have one!
Ay!
Oatmeal.
Food of horses in England
and men in Scotland.
Where else can you find
such horses or such men?
- Mr.!
- "Sir" to you.
- Have some porridge.
- No way.
Did you write that?
Listen!
I think I'm gonna make into you,
and I'm telling you.
Seeing you're new here,
and I am an old hand...
Did you like it?
British bacteria
and what they do.
- You're daft.
- I beg your pardon?
Nuts is the word, in English.
Keep your dirty hands off my breakfast!
You'll be fired.
I smell it.
You'll loose that smile
on your face when the
boss and the Provost
have read the article.
You're done for!
You'll see! Done for!
Where is the golf course?
Fore!
Ouch!
What the...
- I'm awfully sorry.
- Oh, it's you, it's quite all right...
You were a little late with your "fore".
And you were a bit early with your "out".
- Donald, please...
- Well, anyway, why aren't you working?
Donald and I are taking the morning off.
Would you care to join us?
Yes, I'd love to!
Pity I lost my ball.
Yes, it do seem to be lying pretty badly.
Not lying too well, I know.
- Let's put two more down!
- Yes.
Come on, Donald, bring the cup.
- Do show me the way!
- Right!
Pass me your club.
And the ball.
Your game was bad enough when you were
by yourself, what will it be now?
Sorry about that business
of Mrs. Hegarty's dog.
Yes.
Still, something ought to be done about it.
I'm sorry, you're trying to play.
Oh, it's quite all right.
Did the Provost go to Croy this morning?
Yes, early, why?
Oh... Nothing.
Mrs. Hegarty! Mrs. Hegarty!
You are in the paper!
What?
With a full page they put you
in the Advertiser.
About me? In the Advertiser?
Tom McWarden, have you a copy
of this illustrious publication?
Not me, Dan McCanny saw
it in the library...
When he was doing his crosswords.
In the library? Tom McWarden,
keep me ice cream warm!
What's this?
Order! Order!
Ohh!
Father blessed in heaven!
If that isn't me name all over the page!
In letters the size of a great whale
itself that swims in the wide oceans.
Scandalous incident over a dog!
Will you listen to this now...
It's high time our local bumbles
learn to administer the law with decency.
What's a bumble?
It was beneath the Provost's dignity
to set her mind at rest...
It wasn't beneath his dignity
to kick her out of doors.
He kicked her out as if she were
a complete stranger.
Wasn't that awful?
Tonight, this dull bully is holding
a political meeting...
To make a grand parade of his principles...
They are not good enough
for us, and neither is he.
Silence!
Silence in the room!
Congratulations!
A magnificent fellow.
If we could only apply
the knowledge and energy...
That has come to the
breeding of that animal...
To the improving of the human stock...
We could have something like that
in three generations.
- Well, thanks for the game.
- We'll have another when you've the time.
Yes, I think I'll have the time.
Victoria!
- What are you doing here with that man?
- You know Mr. Burdon?
- I am one of the untouchables.
- I'll say you are!
Haven't you heard? Something
terrible has happened.
Horace is off his head!
Oh, no, Lisbeth!
Have you had the doctor?
Don't be silly! Drive me home
and I'll tell you.
And Horace will deal with you, you cad.
- What on hearth?
- Get on, Vickie!
Oh, won't Willie ask the same!
Mr. Chairman, ladies and gentlemen...
These are exceptional times...
And they require exceptional...
Require exceptional...
Exceptional measures!
And exceptional men...
Pause for applause.
- Ah, my friends...
- Were you speaking?
- I was not.
- It must have been the differential.
Will you see the young gent
that called yesterday?
- What young gent?
- Him from the newspaper.
- Then he can't come in.
- Right-o.
- And don't say "right-o".
- OK!
He's in!
How dare you come and see me?
I haven't.
I came to see the Provost.
Well, he's not back.
You go straight to the Hall.
I just want to give him an explanation.
I suppose you mean an apology?
No, an explanation.
I better go, it can't be very pleasant
for you to see me.
I suppose you know what you've done?
You've slandered a fine honourable man.
It's despicable.
What harm has my father
ever done to you?
To me...
No harm.
So why did you stabbed him
in the back like this?
Why did you do it?
It's hard to explain...
No decent action is ever hard to explain.
No, perhaps not.
You don't mean that idiotic business
about that dog?
You think it's idiotic?
- Well it's so... So small!
- Oppression is never small.
Oh, of course but...
It doesn't make sense!
You lose your job,
you'll never get another one...
And all because you got sentimental about
this silly old woman and her mongrel dog.
So did you, you stuck up for her.
Well, I tried to clear up after the Provost
had asserted his authority.
That's what women are for!
Ah, that's what women are for, are they?
Why did you do it?
Don't be the demure, I'm
trying to help you.
Are you?
Are you? Why?
Never mind why...
What sort of man are you anyhow?
Did you ever know a decent
hearted chap who could tell
you straight off what sort
of a decent chap he was?
I've never knew a man do the mischief
you've done for no reason at all.
Well, look here...
If you really want to know,
I'll tell you something I never told...
No, well... Goodbye.
Tell me!
Well...
When I was a kid...
I lived at the foot of a steep hill.
Carts used to go up the
hill with heavy loads.
Sometimes the horses couldn't take the
loads and the carters used to hit them.
On their flanks, on their bellies,
on their eyes and nostrils.
One day I couldn't
take it any longer...
I was tearful out of my life,
I went for one of the carters.
He then put the flat of his hand against my
face and sent me spinning into the gutter.
So I said to myself...
When you grow up, you will hit out.
Every time, no matter what it costs.
And you've done that?
Yes.
Get in.
What has the Advertiser come to?
I was away!
It was a great shock to me!
What shall we do?
Does the Provost know?
I couldn't say.
My, but it's awful, awful!
Horace, I want to talk to you.
Willie is not here yet.
He won't think I'd anything to do with it?
- Oh, don't be stupid!
- I wonder if he's seen it.
Well, if he hasn't we don't tell him now,
not before his speech.
Here he is.
Hail!
- Hello, Father.
- Hello, Vickie.
Hello, Burdon! That was a good
job you made of our interview.
You made the corrections and the proof?
Yes.
Hello, Lisbeth!
Hello, Callender! A great night, hey?
Hello, Horace!
We want our Willie!
Did you hear them?
Did you hear that?
Oh, they're Calling for their Willie.
Well they shall have their Willie!
Ladies and gentlemen...
Our speaker tonight...
Needs very little introduction
from me.
There's no one who's
done more for Baikie...
Than Provost Gow.
Hear, hear!
- Sit down.
- No!
Tonight...
I want you to show him what you
really think of him in your hearts.
As the old man so wisely said...
Oh what some power that's good to have...
To see ourselves as others see us.
Yes...
Now you give the Provost the power
to see himself...
As you see him tonight.
Provost Gow!
Mr. Chairman, ladies and gentlemen.
I think I may call you my friends.
I'm sure I may call you my friends.
For what is friendship...
But the will to do,
and the power to do...
The best a man can, for those with whom
he's associated!
It is a sacred bond...
A beautiful relationship...
What's the matter with them, Skirving?
A sacred bond, a beautiful relationship.
We live my friends, in exceptional times.
And such times require
exceptional measures.
Ah, my friends...
What is needed today, is a
firm hand at the helm.
A man who'll go on and on,
and up and up...
On and on, and up and up...
Always keeping before him...
The best interests of the
whole community.
It will be the duty of such a man
to protect the oppressed...
For what...
For what is a man's
strength given to him...
If he doesn't hold out a helping hand!
Oh where, oh where
has my little dog gone?
Oh where, oh where can he be?
With his ears cut short
and his tail cut long.
Oh where, oh where can he be?
Bau, Bau, Patsy has floppy ears...
Bau, Bau! Bau, Bau!
He hasn't got his tax...
So she could not get him back...
But he could kick her out, Bau, Bau!
Who's given permission of issue?
I never saw the like
in 40 years of Scotch politics.
Scottish, man, Scottish!
Who wrote this filth?
I'm afraid I did.
- You did?
- Yes, he did.
Your traitorous little sneak.
- You dirty rat!
- Oh, father, don't! What's the use?
- Hey, you keep out of this...
- Listen, Mr. Gow...
- You snivelling little scoundrel!
- You see, Victoria, it's no use.
- Don't you dare to address my daughter!
- But you won't listen to me.
- Listen to you, you puke little libeller?
- Shut up.
- What did you say?
- I said: Shut up.
- Oh father, do stop!
- Victoria, I think you are the limit.
Go on Willie, give the little bum
the hiding he deserves.
Yes I can...
I'll tell you what I'll do to you, you...
Be careful chum,
I'm rather good at this!
Mr. Provost! Oh, Mr. Provost!
The sergeant says
will you leave the building!
What do you mean, of course
I'll leave the building!
Ay, but the sergeant says will you go out
by the back way?
The back way? What for?
The riot's getting out of hand!
- They are throwing stones.
- They're trying to break in!
I'll show the rubble
what I think of them.
Willie, what are
you going to do?
- I'll show them who's Provost Gow!
- Willie!
They can't carry on
like a lot of hooligans in my town!
Father don't do this, you'll get hit!
I'll deal with you in the morning.
And that goes for me!
- But Sergeant said...
- Oh, shut up!
Victoria...
You might've saved us this anyway!
- Open the door!
- But can't show yourself to them, Mr. Gow.
- You can' show yourself out there!
- Open that door!
For you.
Dear Miss Gow, I had nothing to
do with last night, honestly.
Your sincerely, Frank Burdon.
Father...
About last night...
If there is one thing that I can't
tolerate is disloyalty.
Not content with playing
golf with the fellow?
Who told you about that?
- Lisbeth, I suppose.
- She does know what loyalty is!
Well after all, it was before I knew
about the article.
Was it after you knew that you brought him
out to the platform?
How was I to know that people were
going to jeer at you?
Don't exaggerate Vickie, please!
And it wasn't the people.
It was a put up job organized
by that unprincipled little scum.
More coffee, please.
Mr. Burdon had nothing
to do with it.
He hadn't? And nothing to do
with the article, I suppose?
I know, I know.
But I have discussed the
whole thing with him...
- You discussed it with him?
- Yes.
- This morning he write to say...
- Oh he writes!
How nice!
Anyway, if you had done the right thing,
you would have paid the fine yourself.
It's all rather trivial.
Look at this!
In the Scottish edition
of a London newspaper.
Good heavens!
Willie, have you seen this?
Scottish candidate barked down!
They think that's funny?
What's going to happen
at the dinner tonight?
Lord Skerryvore... Party.
Something's got to
be done and done quickly.
Horace is taking Burdon
down to your office.
Good. I'll break that fellow!
You'd better be careful.
I don't think you know Mr. Burdon.
Now Mr. Burdon, I'm going
to ask you a few questions.
And I'll advise you to stick to the truth.
Where are we, Berlin, Moscow, or where?
- You'll find out where you are.
- Surely enough!
Oh I'm Nordic, if that's
what's worrying you.
- That's enough!
- That will do!
Be quite, you little cad!
Come on now...
How much did they pay you?
- Or was it affect job?
- It's blackmail!
- What are you talking about?
- You needn't act the innocent.
We know who's backing you Burdon!
Come on, speak up man!
What exactly was it worth to you?
Oh no, you don't!
We haven't finished with you yet,
not by a long chalk.
The opposition paid you
to get that muck into the Advertiser?
- You were at the back of the raw too.
- The plotter master?
So you don't deny it!
I wouldn't spoil your fun.
It will be no fun for you, you're
going to sweat for this.
I came here out of my own free will
trying to help you out of your mess...
Heaven knows why I should.
- But after you childish insinuations...
- Wait!
This is a withdrawal of the statements
you made in your article.
And you're going to sign it!
I'll read it to you.
- I, the undersigned...
- You needn't trouble.
No, no, of course not, it's quite in order.
- So sign at the bottom.
- Are you being serious?
- What do you mean?
- No!
- What do you mean no?
- I mean I won't sign it or anything else!
- You won't sign it?
- No I don't well want.
- You mean you refuse?
- That's what I'm trying to convey.
But why not?
Because everything word
that I wrote was true.
- Do you know what you'll get you in for?
- No, I don't care!
- You can consider yourself fired!
- I considered myself that yesterday!
- You won't find another job!
- We'll see to that!
I'm sure you will.
I suppose you know this
means an action for...
- Slander.
- Ay, slander.
And not only civil action,
but criminal proceedings.
And 10 years penal
service, 20 lashes, three
times a day, out of
food, I don't care!
Listen, Mr. Gow...
You're not a bad chap at hearth,
but you got to remember one thing...
The people of this country is the most
long suffering on God's earth.
They'll put up with humbug, hypocrisy,
shilly-shallying and hardship.
They'll pull in their belts
if they think it's their duty.
They'll go to the four corners of the earth
and get blown to bits if need be...
But two things they will not stand.
Bullying and cruelty.
And if you've forgotten that, I'll make it
my business to remind you.
I told you to be careful.
What's more, I think he is quite right!
You - are-having fun.
- Blowing off steam?
- Yes!
- That's assuredly furious.
But you haven't the vaguest idea
what to do about it.
- It's nice breaking china, isn't it?
- I wish it was his neck.
- Father's?
- Yes!
Aren't you being a little childish?
Allow me!
Thank you.
I suppose your pride denies to have
anyone daring to suspect your motives.
You must admit it's
a bit hard for any
ordinary person not to
think you were bribed.
Don't break this one.
Oh, allow me!
Thank you.
You've got yourself into a
nice mess, haven't you?
- I won something!
- Never mind that.
What are you going to do?
Look for another job, I suppose.
If you can get one.
And what are you going
to do in the meanwhile?
You got any money at all?
- Cigarette?
- No thanks. You may need them.
Frank!
Don't get excited, I want
to ask you a question.
- Yes, but you-you called me Frank.
- Well?
- That's my name.
- So I thought!
But it's the first time
you've used my name.
Well what about it?
- It's the first time you call me Frank.
- Oh, do listen...
Yes, well... Lend me another penny.
There!
It's difficult to ask you this, you
mustn't misunderstand me.
Do what father asked.
Who have you've taken me for?
One stone, six pounds, four ounces.
Don't be so obstinate!
How can you expect me to bow to him?
You know I'm right, you said so.
I never said you were.
I said your motives were.
Now, don't ask for another one.
Frank, you've made your protest
and it was a fine thing to do.
That's pigheadedness, and there's
nothing new about pigheadedness.
It is old as the pigs.
So is this.
Frank...
Be generous.
Generous?
You gave father a pretty hard
knock, you know.
You made him ridiculous,
it was the worst thing you could do.
Why not call it a day?
What about Patsy?
Oh, put it this way...
If he behaves decently to Mrs. Hegarty...
You'll sign the withdrawal.
Supposing he won't?
- He will.
- He may break his word.
Then we'll both tell the world
what we think of him.
Both?
Then you're in this with me!
A deal.
It's what I'm telling you!
Ice cream flew everywhere
and was rising to the stars...
With the people buzzing around
like it was bees on the honeysuckle...
And me selling ice creams
as it were hot-dog.
Give me my shawl!
I'm making enough money to pay my
fine and get Patsy back to us.
Oh, Mr. Burdon, Your Honour!
They rascals arrested
me goods and chattel!
What's happening, McKeller?
- They're seizing her goods for debt!
- Who are?
- The authorities!
- God, this is fantastic!
Oh it is that, and they're doing in
the wee dog tonight!
Mrs. Hegarty, we're from the London Sun!
- Are you're a reporter?
- Yes!
Come with me. I'll give you the biggest
scoop you ever had in your life.
You better come Mrs.
Hegarty too, and I...
Mr. Burdon, Your Honour, don't be doing
anymore good for me!
I've lost Patsy I've lost me barrow,
there isn't much more I can lose.
Get out of my way!
Get after her, quick.
If your father thinks he's
going to get away with
this, he has made the biggest
mistake of his life.
Don't you wave that thing at me!
The deal is off!
The condemned man ate a hearty meal...
Patsy. Patsy...
In, in!
Honoria!
Meself.
I come to say goodbye.
You didn't say that you were leaving us.
It's goodbye to Patsy, you numbskull.
Well...
Step on it.
They'll be coming for him.
Patsy!
Don't take on, Honoria,
it cannot be helped!
There he lies...
As if he was in his coffin.
Ay...
I'm real sorry, Honoria...
But at least he is not going to suffer
any more like us that stay here.
- That's for true.
- Ay.
What do you say to a wee drink?
Come on, they're open.
No, no, Honoria.
In return for your kindness.
And leave Patsy?
Ah, he'll be all right, you can lock
the door, nobody'll know.
We'll drink to his dear departing spirit.
Sure...
Sure it's only common humanity.
Well... I'll get my keys.
Only a wee, you mind!
Mind this, Honoria...
Only went for a little one...
Just that.
Only one.
I'm seeking you, McKeller.
Oh...
It's you!
Ay, all six of me.
I suppose you know you're keeping
the vet waiting.
Ay, you're keeping the vet waiting.
Shh, shhh!
Have a hearth, have a hearth!
Why cause unnecessary pain?
Hack away, will you!
Come on round to your lodging
and hand him over.
Is he all right, Your Honour?
Shhh.
- Your good health, my dear.
- Thank you, Lord Skerryvore.
- There's a cause!
- We must all drink to that!
- Highlands honours, Mr. Provost!
- Ay! Ay!
Highlands honours!
Health!
Well...
- Very good indeed!
- Very nice!
I'm certain all enjoyed themselves...
Allow me.
Don't take too long with the port,
Lord Skerryvore.
No, I won't.
Ah, Lord...
Bring the cigars, Horace will you?
Come over here, my lord.
Come over here and finish your port
in comfort, will you?
Thank you!
- Cigar, my lord?
- Yes, thank you.
- Cigar?
- Thank you, Horace.
Well, Gow...
I hope you're adopted
as official candidate.
But, I thought that was settled!
Yes, I'd hoped it was, but...
Tell me...
What's all this about a dog?
I don't understand...
I mean is...
You know... At a by-election,
the first thought I have is Party.
It's...
Well what's it all about?
I've heard things!
You know it'd be awkward...
Oh, you mean... Oh that!
Oh that was just storm in a teacup!
A woman refused to pay her dog license...
And some young lad made
a sort of joke about it.
The exuberance of youth, you know...
It wasn't an organized thing?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
The papers made out
there was a bit of a riot.
Riot?
- That wasn't a riot, was it Horace?
- Oh, no, no, no, no.
Just... Just fun and game.
Might I have a drop of whiskey
instead of this port?
Why, of course my lord, please...
Please help yourself, would you?
Thank you.
I understand you're very highly respected
in this neighbourhood, Mr. Gow.
There's no man more respected
in the province.
If you understand, his word is law...
Now, in the development of Baikie, he...
- Popular too.
- Extremely popular.
Extremely popular.
Well, you know, popularity
is a tender plant.
The tactless handling of a situation
my be the end of his.
I told you, Your Lordship, the all childish
affair is finished and done with!
What kind of horn is this?
- What's the meaning of this commotion?
- Really My lord, I...
- Willie! Horace!
- Father, what is it?
Hold that, please!
- Thank you.
- Thank you!
What's all this?
What's that photographer doing here?
Mr. Provost!
Oh Mr. Provost, he is gone!
- He is gone!
- Who's gone?
Patsy, Mr. Provost.
Who is Patsy?
Mrs. Hegarty's lord, Your Dogship.
Storm in a teacup, hey?
Exuberance of youth, hey?
Popular, hey?
Call my car!
- Close the door!
- Come in!
Move it, and help to call them off!
Stop petting the beast!
Put it down, Horace!
Give me my coat!
What are you doing?
Get that dog away, will you?
Your bonnet, my lord.
Lord Skerryvore, please don't go like this,
if you only knew, really...
I mean, rather, it's all a
terrible mistake - You run, my Lord.
You can...
Excuse, my lord!
Oh, Horace, what a tragedy!
Oh, don't be stupid! Come on!
Oh, hello!
I'll never want to see you again!
Go away! Go away!
Let me go!
- Call them off, boys.
- Let's blow up, boys.
What was that?
Oh father, don't take it too hardly,
we all know what you feel!
That's just what you don't!
None of you understand Willie!
- Lisbeth!
- And you are worse than any of them!
You work against your own father, carrying
on with that rotten little bounder.
- Lisbeth, control yourself!
- And you are just as bad!
You are jealous of him because he is a man!
- And you're just a miserable... Fish!
- Lisbeth dear, you're upset...
Stay away, don't touch me!
Oh Willie, my darling, my love!
They can't do this to you!
Here, here, here!
What does that mean?
It means...
That I'm not wanted
in this house.
Here!
Take the first instalment.
Here is yours!
Do you think I'm doing it for money?
Take it
away, all I want's a
couple of quid to live on.
Don't be an ass, why should the Sun
get all this for nothing?
Take it away, give it to anyone you like.
Give to the Royal Hospital
for myopic Pekingeses.
Give it to Mrs. Hegarty!
You're a Procurator Fiscal of the Public
Prosecutor, aren't you?
Yes, but I don't see...
Well, do your duty, man!
You got to prosecute him!
Yes, but on what charges?
Find the charges. That's your job!
- Mr. Burdon...
- What the...
I have an warrant for your arrest.
I must ask you to come with me.
- What for?
- Here, you can't do that!
What's the charge?
Let see the warrant!
Come quietly now.
Hello, Burdon, your troubles have gone by.
This is Mr. Watkins
of the FFFFFFF...
The Federation of Friends of the Feathered
Fowl Forbidden Fare, you know.
- God!
- Mr. Burdon...
My society is full with admiration
for your great work on this Patsy case.
We feel that you've fought alone
an unequal battle too long.
I'm authorized to inform
you that my Federation
has decided to take up
the case officially...
And to finance your defence.
Mr. Burdon, we couldn't do otherwise!
The enthusiasm of our members!
We've made Patsy an
honorary vice-president.
- We've also...
- Go, go, go to...
Go away!
I'm fed up with the whole business!
If I wanted to become a publicity
stunt to raising funds
for your federation of futile
fatheads, I'll let you know!
You made a national
entertainment out of what
was only a honest,
straightforward issue!
And you want to use it to push
your fools' society!
Well, I won't have it!
I don't care if I win the case or lose it!
I've lost everything over this.
I've lost my job, I've lost
my future, I've lost...
Oh, take them away.
Mr. Burdon, you can't behave like this!
And you can't take things like that!
My society is going to defend you,
whether you like it or not!
Come along, sir.
It's downright unacceptable, so it is...
To see you gazing there at nothing.
As if you were Columbus taking
his first look at America...
And the dear hearth of you
broken at the fight of this.
Come on, man dear!
Don't be refusing the help of others
from the sorrows on you!
And stand up for yourself
with all your forces...
The way you stand up for others.
The widows and the orphans,
the poor and the helpless.
Listen.
I've caused enough trouble.
I'm through.
I don't care what they do,
I don't want to win the case.
I don't want to do anymore
to hurt Miss. Victoria.
Ah, it's the great boy you are, Mr. Burdon.
And it's a great gift for
right that you have.
Did I tell you, I had the article framed?
It's up on the wall,
between His Holiness...
And the colour enlargement
of poor Hegarty that was?
It's a cruelty, that's what it is.
It makes me boil over!
Such a sweet little doggie, my dear.
Yes!
I know what I'd do with
that Provost of Baikie.
- Doing a thing like that to a dog!
- Bad show!
And shall poor Patsy die...
The twenty million schoolchildren
shall learn to read and fight.
I mean it's hardly
playing the game, what?
- It's not cricket!
- No.
The Patsy case.
It is understood that reports of the
resignation of Provost William Gow...
Were officially denied
in Baikie today.
The Court!
Bring him up.
Bring up the penal Frank Burdon.
Bring up Frank Burdon.
I brought myself up!
They might have given me some red finery
and a choir in the orchestra.
This is a court of law, there is
no orchestra whatever.
- Then there should be.
- You be quiet!
Inasmuch as you've acted to publish a
statement designed out carefully...
To exercise an improper influence
on the voters in parliamentary election...
Under the Corruption and Illegal
Practices' Act of 1895.
When?
1895!
But I wasn't born then!
- Have you understood the charge?
- I tried to.
Do you want it read again?
No, thank you.
Do you plead guilty or not guilty?
Does it matter?
The defendant pleads not guilty, my lord.
You know that.
- We may proceed?
- Why not?
Thank you.
Call Robert Andrews.
Robert Andrews!
- Do brisk up, Willie.
- I wish I could see Victoria.
Oh her, she won't turn up anyway.
Willie...
When you've won your case,
Horace may call off the divorce.
Sometimes I think you're without
one moral principle!
And nothing but the truth?
And nothing but the truth.
- You're Robert Andrews?
- I am!
You are a composer, working
for the Baikie Advertiser?
I am!
Then you set up in print the
matter appearing in the paper?
I do!
On the night in question, were you given by
the penal a last minute article to set up?
I was!
Was the penal the author of the article?
Silence!
How dare you!
I'm trying to save time.
When I defend a case, I expect my client
to behave himself.
I didn't ask you to, I can defend myself.
Mr. Burdon, there are 3000 pounds put
forward for your defence by the FFFFF...
You all know where that's going to.
Really!
Leave him to me, Mr. Menzies.
Mr. Burdon, you must not
interrupt the hearing.
Go on.
How did you know the penal
was the author of the article?
It was his English and the writing.
What do you mean by that?
Read it and you'll understand.
I understand you had difficulties
in deciphering the article.
It was practically a
physical impossibility.
You're quite sure you sent the print
What the penal wrote?
Of course he did!
- Keep quiet!
- I corrected the proof myself!
Hold your tongue!
Well, don't suggest I didn't
write what I did write.
Shhh.
You really must speak to
your client, Mr. Menzies.
My lord, you told me to leave him to you.
Don't be impertinent.
Silence!
The next person to laugh, will be
turned out of this court.
Yes, sir.
Vickie!
Why...
I thought you weren't coming.
What else could I do?
I've missed you, Vickie.
It was decent of you to have
kept away from... Him.
You are mistaking him Vickie.
He's just a self seeking little rattler.
He is nothing of the kind.
He didn't do anything
you didn't goad him to.
And you're bringing this case
simply to satisfy your own pride.
I see!
So you're still taken
in with the fellow.
Well, it'll interest you to know
where I've got him this time.
Father!
- You're Margaret Twine?
- Sure!
Please... Just answer yes or no.
OK.
You're employed as a parlour
maid by Provost Gow?
Says you!
What is the meaning of
this expression "says you"?
Well...
My lord...
It's as slang phrase of American origin
which has gained regrettable currency...
In the language of our people through
the insidious agency of the city mob.
And it will, I'm given to understand,
employed to indicate...
A state of dubiety in the mind
of the speaker, as to the...
Veracity or credibility of
a statement made to him.
Oh, yeah?
Honoria Hegarty!
I'm here right now me Sarge!
Don't be raising the roof!
The court's waiting. Where
on earth have you been?
I had to get my Patsy at the nursing home.
The publicity got on the nerves of him
and he had to have a rest cure.
You're lucky not to get six months
for contempt of Court.
Well, I don't know about the six months...
But I got the contempt all right!
- And I will tell the truth...
- Tell the truth.
- The whole truth...
- The whole truth.
- And nothing but the truth.
- Nothing but the truth.
- Thank you.
Your name, I believe, is Honoria Gakin.
Or Hegarty.
Aw, make up your mind
man, which it is Hegarty, it is.
Now, on the evening under discussion,
you paid a visit to Mr. Gow's house.
- Clydeview, McCullan Row.
- I did enough!
You've cause to remember that evening.
Cause of it!
And he pushing me back, hitting every step!
And I got a great large bruise
the colour of a rainbow in the sky.
It's not faded away yet,
look if you could only see...
Yes, but never mind about that.
Oh, it's easy for you to talk...
- Couldn't I get in, please?
- What's your involvement in the case?
- Yes, but I...
- Nay, nay...
You'll have to wait until you're called.
And now...
We've come to the evening of the...
The canine demonstration at Mr.
Gow's house.
Now, tell me.
On that day, did the accused express
animosity against Provost?
Sure all the animals, and the lions better
than lambs, are against the Provost.
Thank you, that will do.
Mr. Menzies, do you wish
to question the witness?
Certainly not, my lord.
Indeed I've been waiting
with all the patience I can
muster to hear why the Crown
has called this rather...
Irrelevant lady.
Oh! Patsy!
Did you hear what he called me?
- Yes, she must stand down.
- God bless you, Your Honour.
And Her Ladyship...
If so be there's such a lucky woman...
As to be wed to Your Holiness.
Michael Cassidy.
From his rump to his
shoulders is a sheepdog...
But he got the muzzle of a Cheshire
and the ears of cocker spaniel.
But the expression is
of an Irish terrier...
And he's holding the
tail like a Pomeranian.
And he's got the sad,
noble eyes of a poodle.
In fact he's not so much a dog...
But a summary of all the dogs that ever
roamed these lands on four legs.
- And what's he worth?
- Six shillings and eight pence.
My lord...
What has this to do with the case?
I'm establishing motives
by a process of elimination.
Must you eliminate the entire population of
the British Isles and the Irish Free State?
My lord, I object to this witness.
I don't.
- What did you say?
- I said I've no objection.
- Are you going to keep quiet?
- Fairly, not altogether.
- I'll abandon the case.
- Good.
Really! My Lord!
Now, now, Mr. Burdon, you mustn't speak
like that, you know?
I realize you're a very young man.
And indeed I sometimes fail to fathom
the younger generation.
It seems to have no balance, no stability.
What with swing music,
automatic gambling machines...
And the encouragement given
to idleness and lose
living by the British
Broadcasting Corporation.
What are you laughing, Mr. Menzies?
Was I laughing, my lord?
You made a sort of gesture
with your features...
That I've always taken as an
expression of amusement.
I'm unaware of anything amusing
in what I'm saying.
I hardly referred to your words, my lord.
Perhaps you'll refrain from
sniggering until you find
yourself in a more suitable
place for that exercise.
With all respect, Your
Lordship misapprehended
the exact nature
of the gesture...
As to which Your Lordship
was pleased to refer.
The matter is that I...
I was stifling an insistent yawn.
Indeed, Mr. Menzies?
Perhaps Your Lordship will now
revise your pronouncement
as to the suitable place
for that exercise.
If you wish me, Mr. Menzies, to recount the
uses for which this place is suitable...
I'm quite prepared to do so.
For one thing it is
suitable for the exercise
of your undoubted talent
as defending council.
Talent which I may remark
I have not observed to
be conspicuously employed
on this particular case.
My lord...
Your Lordship's opinion of
my poor capabilities...
Expressed as I may say in all
sincerity with the terseness
and clarity that are the
credit to the Scottish bar...
Has left me with no alternatives
than to withdraw from the case.
I have been grievously insulted.
Good Morning!
But Mr. Menzies...
Silence!
And now, my lord, may I defend myself?
Well, I can't stop you.
You may leave the dock
and get close to your solicitor.
- Do you think that will hurt...
- On behalf of the FFFFF...
Don't spit at me, sir!
- But you see...
- I don't want to hear another word.
- What happened?
- Willie, Burdon's defending himself!
What?
They have adjourned while the fool
consults his solicitor.
I'm delighted to hear it!
- Hello!
- Hello.
- Vickie!
- Nice of you to pop in.
I thought you didn't want to see me again.
- This is a public court, isn't it?
- So you've come to see me hanged.
It looks like it.
You seem determined to
throw away your case.
It's my case isn't it?
Don't be a fool, Frank.
Do I hear you call me Frank?
Here, here, you can't talk to a witness
for the prosecution.
Are you a witness?
Well, yes I am, but...
I see that your father has
dragged you into it now!
Don't see things like that!
I can't help it and I've been
called by the Crown and I...
I understand, you're entitled
to say and do exactly what you like.
Mr. Burdon I've been looking
for you everywhere.
Now, do you know what to do?
I know what to do all right!
Father...
I beg you, don't go on with this case...
What?
Of course I shall go on with it!
In the case I wont, it isn't my case,
but the Crown will.
The court is in session!
The law has been set in motion
and the law must operate.
I intend to be vindicated!
But father, you must listen to me!
Don't take any notice of her, Willie.
William Gow!
No, no.
Oh, Mr. Skirving, can you help me?
I must get into the Court and they
won't let me in because I'm witness.
Oh, I see.
I'll just keep them busy and you slink in.
- Oh, thank you.
- Victoria, listen...
Don't think too hardly of Lisbeth.
- I won't.
- Donald!
Yes, sir?
How are you keeping?
- Oh, bonnie man, bonnie!
- Fine, fine!
Tell me, how is that wee daughter of yours,
getting on with the ballet dancing?
Oh, mighty grand, she's just a picture!
In short, you've the strongest
reason to believe...
That you've been the victim of deliberate
and persistent persecution.
- Absolutely!
- Thank you.
Mr. Burdon, do you to cross-examine?
I'll say I do.
Silence!
Now, Mr. Gow...
When did this so-called persecution start?
The night you organized a pack of hooligans
to break up my meeting.
Oh, no, no, before that.
What about my article, wasn't that
part of the persecution?
- Certainly it was.
- Then I'll ask you again.
When did the persecution start?
I suppose you want me to say when
Mrs. Hegarty came to my house.
Exactly.
She came to you very distracted.
No doubt. But she didn't take her grievance
to the proper quarter.
Didn't she?
Weren't you the Provost,
the father of his people?
Yes, but if I happen to be distressed by...
a burst pipe line...
I don't take my distress
to the Prime Minister.
I'd get a plumber, in a manner
of speaking, my lord.
Well, in a manner of speaking, sir...
Mrs. Hegarty has probably thought
you were the plumber.
Mr. Burdon.
Silence!
So you were surprised the day after Mrs.
Hegarty's
visit, when your meeting
refused to listen to you.
Nothing surprises me in Baikie.
So they didn't surprise
you they dished a
strong line with a
chanting of humbug hoots.
My lord, I object.
Mr. Burdon, I oft had
to warn you that this
sort of thing is impacting
very unfavourably.
Very unfavourably indeed. Go on.
So you vented your annoyance
on a poor woman and her dog.
- You took her barrow.
- I did nothing of the sort!
- As for being a poor woman...
- You took her barrow.
She seems to have done very well out of it.
That isn't slander of her, Mr. Gow?
Hear, why do you suppose the whole town
turned against you all of a sudden?
Because you deliberately pitched yourself
to make trouble.
What do you suppose my motive
was for that?
How should I know?
Self-advertisement, I should think.
I did it because I'm an
ordinary sort of man.
When I see a bully and coward...
Behave yourself Mr, Burdon,
you're throwing over your case.
I'm trying to get out the truth!
Why can't he be a man?
Why do you go sneaking on persecuting
widows and little mongrel dogs?
- My lord, I object.
- For your own sake, control yourself.
I'll stand up to anyone
who hits above the belt.
Who hit you below the belt?
- You did.
- In what way?
You wormed all the way
into my family circle...
Stop that!
I won't have your...
Family circle mentioned in this court.
You won't have it!
If you'd shown a little
decent feeling earlier on...
Stop, stop.
What's all this about Mr.
Gow's family circle?
Ask him!
My lord, the reference
must be to Mr. Gow's
daughter, she's a witness
of the prosecution.
Yes, my lord, that's the sort of man he is.
- Mr. Burdon!
- But it's scandalous!
- Quieter!
- I won't be quiet!
I'm calling her next, my lord.
No, you are not!
Silence!
Come out here, you.
Now.
Who are you and what did you say?
I am Mr. Gow's daughter and I said
I wasn't being called as a witness.
Why not, pray?
Because I can't give evidence.
Yes you can, we'll see about that!
- Oh, but I can't!
- And why not?
Because...
The... Accused and I are husband and wife!
Silence!
But is this true?
Yes!
My lord... I must ask for an adjournment.
But I can't keep on adjourning!
- But my lord, this is a profound shock.
- Very well.
Shhh! Shhhh!
They are married!
Ay, and a wife can't give evidence against
her husband, that's the law!
Call Mr. Burdon here at once.
You can't do that, sir.
It's most irregular.
Do as I tell you!
Yes, sir.
- Vickie...
- I'll tell you what, Willie!
Don't start jammering at me!
You've done a nice thing!
But I asked you not
to go on with the case!
Why didn't you tell me?
I can't have a son in
law serving six months.
You sent for me?
What do you mean by marrying my daughter?
- I haven't.
- What?
I only just said that.
We haven't seen each other
since I left the house.
But why in heavens name?
- To stop you.
- Hmm.
To save you both from your stupid pride.
But...
Do you realize what she's done?
They can have her for contempt...
For...
My...
It's worse, it's perjury!
Yes!
Oh...
Stop the case!
What? I can't stop the case,
I won't stop the case!
- Willie!
- For insufficient evidence!
Very well, I'll put you back in the bar.
Willie!
- No you won't!
- Oh, you can't make a fool of the Crown!
You can't force me!
And you can't bully me.
You go back in that dock, for longer.
- Very well!
- Willie!
Oh, go to blazes, woman.
Horace!
He called me a woman.
It's all right, my dear.
Now, Mr. Gow...
The news just heard it has caused
a great shock to you.
No!
Silence!
Do you mean to tell the
Court that you condone
this manoeuvre on the
part of the penal?
Yes!
Silence!
Mr. Gow, it was with your
consent that this scandal...
- My lord, may I make a statement?
- My lord, I protest!
Go on, Mr. Gow.
I want to say...
That in my considered opinion...
Mr. Burdon was fully justified in
all the actions he took against me.
I think... Mr. Burdon misjudged me.
But he misjudged me without malice.
Hurrah for the Provost!
Clear the court! Clear the court!
Clear the Town! Clear the Town!
I hadn't fully realized that a public man
is apt to get above himself.
I'm grateful to Mr. Burdon
for bringing me back to earth.
In regard to Mrs. Hegarty...
And her dog Patsy...
I forgot to apply one of the
great principles of my life.
It is this:
It is only the realization...
The sympathetic realization...
A deep and sympathetic realization...
That each unit in the State...
Is a living, breathing, soul.
Each with his own aspirations...
Each with his own peculiarly
intense perception...
Of his own rights and his own wrongs.
A leader must have that
strange sixth sense...
That enables him to see into
the hearths of his people.
To feel in his own flesh...
And in his own blood...
The wounds and the stresses they suffer.
To a leader...
These English subtitles
from 2014 are the first
ever made since the
film's release in 1937.
They are intended as a
tribute to Vivien Leigh.
Regrettably, they are by a
non-native English speaker...
and therefore as close to the script
as permitted by spots of dense
dialect, obsolete idioms, indistinct
diction and poor sound quality.